<resources>
    <string name="app_name">War Survival Guide – Be Prepared</string>
    <string name="category_icon">Category icon</string>
    <string name="lesson_bombing_safety">Stay Safe During Bombings: Seek shelter in basements or sturdy buildings, avoid windows, and lie flat on the ground.</string>
    <string name="lesson_improvised_shelter">Improvised Shelters: Use furniture, mattresses, or debris to create barriers. Stay low and cover your head.</string>
    <string name="lesson_water_purification">Water Purification: Boil water for 1 minute or use purification tablets. Filter through cloth if cloudy.</string>
    <string name="lesson_handle_fear">Handling Fear: Practice deep breathing, focus on tasks, and stay with others for support.</string>
    <string name="tip_signal_help">Signal for Help: Use mirrors, flashlights, or bright cloth to attract attention during daylight.</string>
    <string name="tip_light_signals">Light/Smoke Signals: Three flashes or smoke puffs in a row signal distress universally.</string>
    <string name="tip_stay_hidden">Stay Quiet/Hidden: Avoid unnecessary noise, cover reflective surfaces, and move at night if possible.</string>
    <string name="plan_blocked_path">Blocked Paths: Identify alternate routes in advance, carry a small tool to clear debris.</string>
    <string name="plan_danger_zones">Danger Zones: Avoid open areas, bridges, and military targets. Stay near cover.</string>
    <string name="plan_stay_in_groups">Stay in Groups: Travel with others for safety, assign roles, and agree on meeting points.</string>

    <string name="lesson_food_rationing">Ration Food: Eat smaller meals, prioritize non-perishables like canned food or dry grains.</string>
    <string name="lesson_noise_control">Stay Quiet: Minimize noise to avoid attracting attention in hostile environments.</string>
    <string name="lesson_blackout_rules">Blackout Windows: Use blankets or dark cloths to block light at night.</string>
    <string name="lesson_first_aid_basics">Basic First Aid: Clean wounds with clean water, apply pressure to stop bleeding, and bandage properly.</string>
    <string name="lesson_escape_plan">Create an Escape Plan: Know multiple exit routes and designate a meeting point with family.</string>
    <string name="lesson_emergency_contacts">List Emergency Contacts: Write important numbers on paper in case devices fail.</string>
    <string name="lesson_hidden_storage">Hide Essentials: Store ID, cash, or food in unexpected, secure spots.</string>
    <string name="lesson_signal_mirror">Signal with Mirror: Use reflective surfaces to catch attention of rescuers in daylight.</string>
    <string name="lesson_dust_mask">Use Dust Masks: Protect lungs from smoke, dust, or chemical exposure.</string>
    <string name="lesson_radio_updates">Listen to Radio: Tune into local frequencies for updates during blackouts.</string>
    <string name="lesson_mobile_battery">Save Battery: Lower brightness, disable Wi-Fi, and close background apps.</string>
    <string name="lesson_silent_communication">Use Silent Signals: Agree on hand signs or light flashes to communicate discreetly.</string>
    <string name="lesson_stay_low">Stay Low: Crawl close to the ground in smoke or crossfire situations.</string>
    <string name="lesson_medicines_priority">Store Essential Medicines: Keep painkillers, antiseptics, and chronic illness meds.</string>
    <string name="lesson_keep_warm">Stay Warm: Layer clothing and conserve body heat during cold conditions.</string>
    <string name="lesson_safe_meeting_point">Designate Safe Meeting Points: Agree on spots for regrouping after separation.</string>
    <string name="lesson_fake_identity">Fake Identity Option: In extreme danger, having alternate ID info might save you.</string>
    <string name="lesson_map_printout">Carry Printed Maps: Do not rely only on digital navigation in war zones.</string>
    <string name="lesson_travel_at_night">Travel at Night: Use darkness as cover when escaping hostile areas.</string>
    <string name="lesson_silent_mode">Use Silent Mode: Always keep phones silent to avoid giving away location.</string>
    <string name="lesson_flashlight_cover">Cover Flashlight: Use red cellophane or tape to reduce visibility.</string>
    <string name="lesson_dog_barking_sign">Watch for Dogs: Barking may signal others nearby — stay alert or silent.</string>
    <string name="lesson_disguise_tips">Use Disguises: Blend with locals or avoid uniforms to minimize threats.</string>
    <string name="lesson_sleep_schedule">Sleep in Shifts: If in a group, rotate rest to stay alert 24/7.</string>
    <string name="lesson_protect_documents">Protect Documents: Use waterproof bags for passports, IDs, and licenses.</string>
    <string name="lesson_signal_smoke">Smoke Signals: Create white smoke in open areas to alert air rescue teams.</string>
    <string name="lesson_dry_foods">Use Dry Foods: Beans, rice, oatmeal — easy to store and last long.</string>
    <string name="lesson_local_language">Learn Local Phrases: Basic local language can save your life.</string>
    <string name="lesson_cover_tattoos">Hide Tattoos: They can give away identity or affiliation.</string>
    <string name="lesson_no_fire_inside">Never Light Fire Indoors: Causes smoke, alerting enemies or creating health risks.</string>
    <string name="lesson_find_high_ground">Find High Ground: Ideal for signaling and observing movement.</string>
    <string name="lesson_scout_area">Scout First: Send one person to check routes or buildings before entering.</string>
    <string name="lesson_keep_quiet_zone">Establish Quiet Zones: Especially at night, prevent unnecessary noise.</string>
    <string name="lesson_secure_doors">Secure Doors: Use furniture, bars, or ropes to keep unwanted entry out.</string>
    <string name="lesson_fake_presence">Fake Occupancy: Leave lights or items to trick others into thinking the area is occupied.</string>
    <string name="lesson_group_strategy">Stick in Groups: Safety improves with numbers; assign roles in emergencies.</string>
    <string name="lesson_reflective_items">Avoid Reflective Gear: It can make you visible to enemies at night.</string>
    <string name="lesson_loose_clothing">Wear Loose Clothing: Easier to move, layer, and conceal items.</string>
    <string name="lesson_learn_first_aid">Learn First Aid Basics: CPR, bleeding control, fractures, burns.</string>
    <string name="lesson_mark_safe_zones">Mark Safe Zones: Use chalk, tape, or landmarks to help navigate.</string>
    <string name="lesson_fake_pathways">Create Fake Trails: Mislead potential trackers using false footprints.</string>
    <string name="lesson_emergency_signals">Use 3 Flashes or 3 Whistles: Standard international distress signal.</string>
    <string name="lesson_scout_night">Scout at Night: Movement is less visible and more cautious.</string>
    <string name="lesson_walk_single_file">Walk in Single File: Reduces noise and visibility when moving in groups.</string>
    <string name="lesson_sharp_objects">Collect Sharp Tools: Knives, scissors, or glass may be used for defense or survival.</string>
    <string name="lesson_reuse_water">Reuse Grey Water: For washing or flushing, not drinking.</string>
    <string name="lesson_hide_tracks">Hide Footprints: Use branches to sweep behind you when fleeing.</string>
    <string name="lesson_avoid_looting">Avoid Looting: Dangerous and often illegal — find alternative sources.</string>
    <string name="lesson_shoes_first">Protect Your Feet: Always have proper shoes for long treks or rubble.</string>
    <string name="lesson_stay_calm">Stay Calm: Panic leads to mistakes — breathe and plan.</string>
    <string name="lesson_scout_food_sources">Scout Abandoned Places: Look for safe, untouched supply locations.</string>
    <string name="lesson_wet_cloth_mask">Use Wet Cloth as Mask: Filters out smoke or dust in air.</string>
    <string name="lesson_bring_photos">Bring Family Photos: Helps in reunification or ID if needed.</string>
    <string name="lesson_know_signals">Know Rescue Signals: Ground-to-air symbols (e.g., “X” means help needed).</string>
    <string name="lesson_write_messages">Leave Written Messages: For family or allies following your trail.</string>
    <string name="lesson_backup_location">Have Backup Shelter: Always plan an alternative place to hide or stay.</string>
    <string name="lesson_boil_everything">Boil All Water: Even rainwater should be boiled to avoid illness.</string>
    <string name="lesson_avoid_conflict">Avoid Fights: Stay low-profile; physical conflict is last resort.</string>
    <string name="lesson_guard_food">Hide Your Food: Insecure storage can attract danger or theft.</string>
    <string name="lesson_undercover_items">Carry Concealed Supplies: Keep essentials hidden under clothing.</string>
    <string name="lesson_alert_codes">Create Alert Codes: Color or number codes to signal urgency in groups.</string>
    <string name="lesson_cold_protection">Prevent Cold Injuries: Keep extremities warm and dry.</string>
    <string name="lesson_hide_in_plain_sight">Hide in Plain Sight: Sometimes blending in is safer than running.</string>
    <string name="lesson_route_memory">Memorize Escape Routes: In case maps or devices fail.</string>
    <string name="lesson_avoid_groups">Avoid Large Groups: Can attract attention or risk spreading panic.</string>
    <string name="lesson_watch_weather">Track Weather: Rain or wind can help cover noise or escape.</string>
    <string name="lesson_under_table">Hide Under Tables: In blasts or gunfire, they offer basic protection.</string>
    <string name="lesson_defensive_posture">Keep Defensive Posture: Protect your head and chest at all times.</string>
    <string name="lesson_make_sling">Make a Sling: For arm injuries using shirt, scarf, or belt.</string>
    <string name="lesson_store_energy">Eat High Energy Foods: Nuts, chocolate, or protein bars.</string>
    <string name="lesson_save_battery">Turn On Battery Saver: Critical during power outages or escape.</string>
    <string name="lesson_solar_charger">Use Solar Chargers: Good for long-term power independence.</string>
    <string name="lesson_hide_cash">Hide Small Cash: Roll it in clothing hems or shoes.</string>
    <string name="lesson_secret_signals">Create Secret Signals: Tap codes, drawn marks, or specific sounds.</string>
    <string name="lesson_headlamp_red">Use Red Light Headlamps: For visibility without detection.</string>
    <string name="lesson_cover_bleeding">Stop Bleeding Fast: Apply pressure for 5+ minutes, elevate limb.</string>
    <string name="lesson_local_plants">Learn Local Plants: Know which are edible, medicinal, or poisonous.</string>
    <string name="lesson_salt_storage">Store Salt: Preserves food and helps with hydration.</string>
    <string name="lesson_fake_id">Carry Fake ID: As backup in extreme identity-risk areas.</string>
    <string name="lesson_mark_exits">Mark Exits: Use glow sticks, chalk, or thread for routes.</string>
    <string name="lesson_treat_burns">Treat Burns: Cool water, avoid ice, cover loosely with cloth.</string>
    <string name="lesson_create_camo">Create Camouflage: Use mud, leaves, or cloth to blend in.</string>
    <string name="lesson_avoid_conflict_zones">Know Conflict Zones: Avoid areas with recent activity or military presence.</string>

    <string name="food_water_store_nonperishable">Stock Non-Perishables: Keep canned foods, dried fruits, and nuts for emergencies.</string>
    <string name="food_water_rationing">Ration Supplies: Distribute food and water wisely to last longer during uncertain times.</string>
    <string name="food_water_water_storage">Store Clean Water: Keep bottled water or fill clean containers for at least 3 days.</string>
    <string name="food_water_purify_boiling">Boil Water: Boil for 10 minutes to kill bacteria and viruses.</string>
    <string name="food_water_use_purification_tabs">Use Purification Tablets: Always carry a few for treating water on the go.</string>
    <string name="food_water_rain_collection">Collect Rainwater: Use clean tarps, buckets, or containers to collect rain safely.</string>
    <string name="food_water_use_filters">Use Water Filters: Portable water filters can make unsafe water drinkable.</string>
    <string name="food_water_stale_bread_tip">Soften Stale Bread: Wrap in a damp cloth and heat to restore texture.</string>
    <string name="food_water_solar_still">Make a Solar Still: Use plastic sheet and containers to distill water using sunlight.</string>
    <string name="food_water_safe_sources">Identify Safe Water Sources: Look for springs or streams away from contamination.</string>
    <string name="food_water_label_supplies">Label Food Supplies: Track expiration and consumption priority.</string>
    <string name="food_water_dont_share_utensils">Do not Share Utensils: Prevent spread of illness in tight conditions.</string>
    <string name="food_water_hide_food">Hide Emergency Food: Store some rations separately in case of raids or loss.</string>
    <string name="food_water_barter_items">Keep Barter Food: Extra salt, sugar, or coffee can be used for trade.</string>
    <string name="food_water_energy_dense">Choose Energy-Dense Foods: Peanut butter, chocolate, and granola offer quick calories.</string>
    <string name="food_water_no_raw_meat">Avoid Raw Meat: Always cook thoroughly to prevent foodborne illness.</string>
    <string name="food_water_preserve_meat">Preserve Meat with Salt: Salt-drying can extend shelf life without refrigeration.</string>
    <string name="food_water_forage_safe_plants">Know Edible Plants: Learn which local greens and roots are safe to eat.</string>
    <string name="food_water_root_storage">Store Roots Underground: Keeps them cool and prevents spoilage.</string>
    <string name="food_water_dont_overeat">Don’t Overeat: Stretch your rations by eating only what’s necessary.</string>
    <string name="food_water_cook_indoors_safely">Cook Indoors Safely: Use small flames with ventilation to avoid smoke.</string>
    <string name="food_water_sterilize_utensils">Sterilize Utensils: Use boiling water or fire to kill germs.</string>
    <string name="food_water_pack_easy_meals">Pack Easy Meals: Focus on simple foods like rice, lentils, or MREs.</string>
    <string name="food_water_avoid_greedy_storage">Avoid Over-Stocking: Heavy storage can slow you down during escape.</string>
    <string name="food_water_check_expiry">Check Expiry Dates: Rotate older items to the front of your stockpile.</string>
    <string name="food_water_fasting_tip">Use Short Fasts Wisely: Fasting for 1-2 days can help stretch supplies when necessary.</string>
    <string name="food_water_rehydrate_food">Rehydrate Dried Foods: Use limited water carefully to revive dried items.</string>
    <string name="food_water_keep_it_dry">Keep Food Dry: Moisture promotes mold and waste.</string>
    <string name="food_water_cook_with_lid">Cook with Lid On: Saves fuel and cooks faster by trapping heat.</string>
    <string name="food_water_dont_waste_crusts">Don’t Waste Crusts or Peels: They offer nutrients and bulk.</string>
    <string name="food_water_wash_produce">Wash All Produce: Even foraged items need cleaning to remove bacteria.</string>
    <string name="food_water_trash_management">Manage Food Waste: Dispose scraps away from shelters to avoid pests.</string>
    <string name="food_water_spice_storage">Store Basic Spices: Salt, pepper, and chili can improve bland food morale.</string>
    <string name="food_water_eat_by_priority">Eat Based on Shelf Life: Fresh foods first, canned goods later.</string>
    <string name="food_water_boil_twice">Boil Twice If Unsure: When water source is highly suspect, double-boil.</string>
    <string name="food_water_fermented_foods">Use Fermentation: Make yogurt or sauerkraut to preserve nutrients.</string>
    <string name="food_water_dont_drink_ocean">Don’t Drink Ocean Water: Salt accelerates dehydration and causes sickness.</string>
    <string name="food_water_bury_food">Bury Extra Food: In sealed containers, it can stay cool and hidden.</string>
    <string name="food_water_cook_bulk">Cook in Bulk: Saves time and fuel if storage allows.</string>
    <string name="food_water_watch_animals">Watch Animal Behavior: They often know clean water sources.</string>
    <string name="food_water_eat_slowly">Eat Slowly: Helps you feel full longer on small meals.</string>
    <string name="food_water_keep_snacks_ready">Keep Quick Snacks Ready: Energy bars or nuts for sudden evacuations.</string>
    <string name="food_water_minimize_spills">Minimize Spills: Every drop of water or grain counts in a crisis.</string>
    <string name="food_water_survival_tea">Make Survival Tea: Boil pine needles or herbs for hydration and vitamins.</string>
    <string name="food_water_wrap_water_bottles">Wrap Water Bottles: Use cloth to keep them cool longer.</string>
    <string name="food_water_use_small_containers">Use Small Containers: Reduces waste when opening food for one.</string>
    <string name="food_water_roast_grains">Roast Grains: Easier to digest and store longer than raw ones.</string>
    <string name="food_water_protect_stash">Protect Food Stash: Lock or disguise it from looters or wild animals.</string>
    <string name="food_water_dry_fruits">Dry Fruits: Apples, bananas, and berries are high-energy, long-lasting food options.</string>

    <string name="communication_keep_radio_handy">Keep a Battery-Powered Radio Handy: Stay updated with emergency broadcasts.</string>
    <string name="communication_use_morse_code">Learn Basic Morse Code: Communicate silently and over long distances.</string>
    <string name="communication_signal_with_light">Use Flashlight Signals: SOS can be signaled with short and long flashes.</string>
    <string name="communication_establish_meeting_point">Establish a Family Meeting Point: If separated, everyone knows where to regroup.</string>
    <string name="communication_backup_phone_list">Write Down Emergency Contacts: Phones may die, memory wont help.</string>
    <string name="communication_powerbanks_ready">Carry Power Banks: Keep your phone charged in blackouts.</string>
    <string name="communication_app_offline_messaging">Use Offline Messaging Apps: Tools like Bridgefy or FireChat work without the internet.</string>
    <string name="communication_social_media_update">Post on Social Media Wisely: Short, clear updates help others know you are safe.</string>
    <string name="communication_daily_checkin">Schedule Daily Check-ins: Confirm safety with trusted contacts at set times.</string>
    <string name="communication_silence_devices">Silence Phones When Hiding: Avoid detection while remaining alert.</string>
    <string name="communication_code_words">Create Code Words: Share sensitive information securely among family or friends.</string>
    <string name="communication_whistle_signals">Use Whistles for Alerts: Long and short bursts can signal different warnings.</string>
    <string name="communication_neighborhood_network">Build a Neighborhood Network: Share info, supplies, and coordinate plans.</string>
    <string name="communication_draw_signs">Draw Simple Signs: Arrows or symbols can guide others silently.</string>
    <string name="communication_mark_safe_zones">Clearly Mark Safe Zones: Label areas that offer shelter or supplies.</string>
    <string name="communication_keep_notes">Keep a Notepad &amp; Pen: When batteries fail, writing persists.</string>
    <string name="communication_tape_messages">Tape Messages on Doors: For evacuation or warnings to others.</string>
    <string name="communication_emergency_broadcasts">Know Emergency Frequencies: Tune into AM/FM or shortwave for updates.</string>
    <string name="communication_cb_radio">Use CB or Ham Radios: Great for long-distance contact without infrastructure.</string>
    <string name="communication_flash_signals">Use Mirrors or Flash to Signal: Reflective light can be seen from afar.</string>
    <string name="communication_shout_only_when_safe">Only Shout When Safe: Verbal communication attracts attention, both good and bad.</string>
    <string name="communication_text_not_call">Text Instead of Call: Texts are more likely to get through when networks are weak.</string>
    <string name="communication_mark_trails">Mark Paths When Moving: Chalk, tape, or arrows help others follow or find you.</string>
    <string name="communication_prep_messages">Pre-write Evacuation Messages: Leave them behind for searchers if you move fast.</string>
    <string name="communication_group_chat">Use Group Chats for Updates: Family members get info instantly when signal allows.</string>
    <string name="communication_signal_fire">Create Smoke Signals or Fires: Can be seen from a distance when safe to do so.</string>
    <string name="communication_code_signals">Use Signal Codes: 3 fires = SOS, 2 = okay, etc. for quick visual understanding.</string>
    <string name="communication_talk_in_whispers">Whisper Indoors: Avoid eavesdropping and minimize sound leaks.</string>
    <string name="communication_low_light_signals">Use Dim Light for Signals at Night: Avoid detection while communicating.</string>
    <string name="communication_sound_familiar">Use Familiar Sounds: Family whistles or claps can replace names.</string>
    <string name="communication_waterproof_notes">Use Waterproof Paper or Bags: Messages won’t be ruined by weather.</string>
    <string name="communication_sticky_notes_in_kit">Keep Sticky Notes in Survival Kit: Leave clear messages behind when fleeing.</string>
    <string name="communication_backup_sim">Carry a Backup SIM Card: Switch if the main carrier is down or blocked.</string>
    <string name="communication_keep_phone_hidden">Hide Phones During Conflict: Avoid seizure or surveillance.</string>
    <string name="communication_trusted_contact">Assign a Remote Trusted Contact: Someone outside the warzone can coordinate help.</string>
    <string name="communication_info_board">Use a Common Info Board in Shelter: Share status, needs, and updates daily.</string>
    <string name="communication_write_on_skin">Write Info on Skin: Last resort when papers or devices are lost.</string>
    <string name="communication_timed_alerts">Set Timed Alerts: Reminders for check-ins or movement without internet.</string>
    <string name="communication_stay_quiet_in_crowd">Stay Quiet in Public Shelters: Loud discussions can cause panic or spread rumors.</string>
    <string name="communication_human_chain">Use Human Chain for Long Distance Messages: Relay info through trusted people.</string>
    <string name="communication_relay_misinformation_warning">Avoid Spreading Rumors: False info can lead to danger or chaos.</string>
    <string name="communication_create_audio_log">Keep Audio Diary: Helps track events, warnings, and plans if written notes fail.</string>
    <string name="communication_brief_radio_time">Limit Radio Time: Conserve battery and avoid detection.</string>
    <string name="communication_hide_antenna">Hide External Antennas: To avoid revealing your location to eavesdroppers.</string>
    <string name="communication_hand_signals">Use Military Hand Signals: Communicate silently during evacuations.</string>
    <string name="communication_sos_pattern">Know SOS Pattern: 3 short, 3 long, 3 short – universal distress signal.</string>
    <string name="communication_white_cloth_message">Wave White Cloth with Message: Indicates help needed when visible from air.</string>
    <string name="communication_flash_communication_kit">Build a Flash Communication Kit: Mirror, whistle, flashlight, and pen ready to go.</string>
    <string name="communication_never_use_real_names">Avoid Using Real Names in Public: Protect identities during conflict.</string>

    <string name="firstaid_learn_cpr">Learn Basic CPR: It can save a life before professional help arrives.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_pack_first_aid_kit">Always Carry a First Aid Kit: Bandages, antiseptics, and basic meds are essential.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_stop_bleeding">Control Bleeding: Apply pressure and elevate the wounded area.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_clean_wounds">Clean Wounds Immediately: Use clean water or antiseptic to prevent infection.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_tourniquet">Use a Tourniquet Only When Necessary: As a last resort to stop severe bleeding.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_know_allergies">Know Your Allergies: Avoid medications or food that can trigger reactions.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_clean_cloth">Use a Clean Cloth for Bandaging: Avoid using dirty fabric on wounds.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_treat_burns">Treat Burns with Cool Water: Avoid ice and use sterile dressing.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_make_bandage">Make Improvised Bandages: Use clean clothing in absence of medical supplies.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_detect_infection">Watch for Infection Signs: Swelling, redness, pus, or fever mean trouble.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_splint_broken_bone">Splint Broken Bones: Use sticks and cloth to immobilize the limb.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_wound_cleaning_schedule">Re-clean Wounds Daily: Prevent long-term infection and sepsis.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_shock">Handle Shock: Keep the person warm, calm, and lying down.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_gloves">Use Gloves While Treating: Minimize infection and disease risk.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_disinfect_tools">Disinfect Tools with Fire or Alcohol: Especially tweezers and scissors.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_painkillers">Use Painkillers Wisely: Control pain, but avoid overuse or dependence.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_rehydrate_patient">Rehydrate During Illness: Use oral rehydration salts or clean fluids.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_store_meds_properly">Store Medications Safely: Away from heat, moisture, and sunlight.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_check_expiry">Check Medicine Expiry Dates: Expired drugs can be ineffective or harmful.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_insect_bite_treatment">Treat Insect Bites: Clean area and apply anti-itch or anti-swelling cream.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_diarrhea">Handle Diarrhea Promptly: Rehydrate and take antidiarrheals if available.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_dress_wounds">Redress Wounds Regularly: Keep clean and observe for changes.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_apply_iodine">Apply Iodine Sparingly: Disinfect open cuts effectively with minimal use.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_herbal_aid">Use Herbal Remedies Safely: Garlic, honey, turmeric for minor wounds or immunity.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_nosebleed">Stop Nosebleeds: Pinch nose and tilt head forward, not backward.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_identify_fractures">Identify Fractures: Swelling, bruising, and pain suggest broken bones.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_clean_hands">Clean Hands Before Touching Wounds: Soap and water or sanitizer.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_manage_fever">Manage Fever: Use cool cloths, stay hydrated, and use paracetamol if available.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_track_dosages">Track Medication Dosages: Avoid overdoses and manage supply carefully.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_hypothermia">Treat Hypothermia: Gradually warm with blankets and dry clothes.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_heatstroke">Treat Heatstroke: Move to shade, use wet cloths, and hydrate slowly.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_antibiotics_safely">Use Antibiotics Only When Needed: Misuse can cause resistance.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_sprain">Handle Sprains with RICE: Rest, Ice, Compression, and Elevation.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_rescue_breathing">Use Rescue Breathing: When there is no pulse or breathing, perform CPR.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_treat_dehydration">Recognize and Treat Dehydration: Dizziness, dry mouth, and fatigue are signs.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_asthma">Handle Asthma: Always have an inhaler or know emergency breathing techniques.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_blister_care">Care for Blisters: Keep clean, do not pop unless necessary, then cover.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_eye_wash">Use Eye Wash or Clean Water for Irritants: Flush out chemicals or debris.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_sanitize_water">Sanitize Water for Wound Cleaning: Boil or use tablets before application.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_label_medications">Label Medications Clearly: Prevent mix-ups in emergencies.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_improvise_tourniquet">Improvise Tourniquets Using Belts or Ties: In absence of proper tools.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_bullet_wound">Handle Bullet Wounds: Apply pressure, keep clean, seek help urgently.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_track_symptoms">Log Symptoms for Medical Help: Write down temperature, pain, or rashes daily.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_make_charcoal_bandage">Use Activated Charcoal for Poison: Only under guidance, helps absorb toxins.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_handle_poisoning">Treat Poisoning Based on Type: Don’t induce vomiting unless advised.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_use_gauze_pad">Use Gauze for Deep Cuts: Helps absorb blood and keep wounds sterile.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_tetanus_info">Be Aware of Tetanus Risk: Deep, dirty wounds may require tetanus shots.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_prepare_emergency_card">Keep an Emergency Card: Blood type, allergies, and conditions noted.</string>
    <string name="firstaid_train_others">Train Family Members in First Aid: Increases survival for everyone.</string>

    <string name="escape_plan_create_exit_plan">Create an Exit Plan: Identify all exits from your home, neighborhood, and city.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_keep_route_map">Keep a Printed Map: Don’t rely solely on digital navigation tools.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_predefine_meeting_point">Define Family Meeting Points: Have safe spots in case of separation.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_drill_routes">Practice Escape Routes: Walk or drive them regularly with family.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_backup_route">Always Have a Backup Route: Main roads may be blocked or dangerous.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_hidden_pathways">Learn Hidden or Less Used Paths: Avoid detection and crowds.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_time_escape">Escape at Strategic Times: Move at dawn or night to avoid chaos.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_travel_light">Travel Light: Pack only essentials to move quickly.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_memorize_landmarks">Memorize Key Landmarks: Useful when GPS fails or signals are jammed.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_list_safehouses">Identify Safe Houses: Locations like embassies, clinics, or friendly homes.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_disguise_appearance">Disguise Your Appearance: Blend in to avoid unwanted attention.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_keep_keys_ready">Keep Keys and Essentials Within Reach: For immediate evacuation.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_wear_comfy_clothes">Wear Durable, Comfortable Clothing: Choose layers and sturdy shoes.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_map_checkpoints">Mark Dangerous Checkpoints: Avoid known military or conflict zones.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_charge_devices">Charge Phones in Advance: Keep power banks as backups.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_observe_patrols">Watch Enemy Patrol Patterns: Escape when guards shift or rest.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_list_contacts">Keep Emergency Contacts Written: Phone numbers in case of mobile loss.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_understand_area">Understand Local Geography: Rivers, forests, and hills can help or hinder escape.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_carry_cash">Carry Local Currency in Small Bills: ATMs and cards may not work.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_silent_exit">Exit Quietly: Avoid noise, bright lights, or attracting attention.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_night_vision">Use Red Lights or Dim Flashlights: Preserve night vision and stay hidden.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_stay_in_group">Escape in Small Groups: Safer and easier to support each other.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_conceal_movement">Stay Low and Concealed: Use ditches, fences, or trees for cover.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_signal_safety">Use Simple Hand Signals: Communicate silently with your group.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_bypass_barricades">Avoid Barricades: May be booby-trapped or heavily guarded.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_check_weather">Check Weather Before Moving: Fog or rain can help or hinder.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_track_supplies">Track Food and Water During Escape: Know what you have and ration wisely.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_watch_airspace">Watch the Sky: Drones or aircraft may indicate unsafe zones.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_use_camouflage">Use Natural Camouflage: Mud, leaves, or fabric to blend with terrain.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_move_in_shifts">Rest in Shifts During Escape: Keep at least one person awake.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_bring_ids">Carry Identification Documents: Useful if stopped or when entering safe zones.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_mark_trails">Mark Trails Secretly: Help others follow without alerting enemies.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_scout_ahead">Send a Scout Ahead: Avoid leading the group into traps.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_watch_animals">Watch Animal Behavior: Unusual activity may warn of danger.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_hide_movement">Avoid Open Areas: Stay near walls or dense cover.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_keep_radio">Carry Portable Radio: Stay updated with safe zone broadcasts.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_avoid_crowds">Avoid Panic Crowds: Stampedes or riots can be deadly.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_fake_identity">Use a Cover Story or Alias: If needed to avoid suspicion.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_leave_no_trace">Leave No Trace: Don’t leave items behind that show your route.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_silent_footwear">Use Soft Shoes for Quiet Movement: Avoid boots or heels when sneaking.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_waterways_escape">Use Waterways If Safe: Rivers or canals may bypass ground threats.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_follow_nature">Use Nature’s Clues: Moss on trees or sun direction to navigate.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_plan_short_rest">Take Short, Safe Rests: Avoid deep sleep in unsafe areas.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_list_border_crossings">Identify Border Crossings: Know procedures and risks involved.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_fake_paths">Create Decoy Paths: Mislead pursuers or enemies if necessary.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_practice_scenario">Run Simulated Escapes: Test plans in calm times to prepare better.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_hide_essentials">Hide Essentials in Multiple Places: Spread risk if caught or robbed.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_encrypt_messages">Use Basic Encryption: Share coordinates or escape notes in code.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_rejoin_after_split">Set Rejoin Protocols: Know what to do if separated from group.</string>
    <string name="escape_plan_use_local_tips">Ask Locals Discreetly: Get recent info on checkpoints and patrols.</string>

</resources>